A Guide to the Papers Ellen Glasgow, 1880-1963
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- PHOTOGRPAHS AND IMAGES
  - 2 photographs of "Green Forest," Glasgow family home in Rockbridge, n.d. (Box 26)
  - Photograph of pencil drawing of Thomas Hardy, n.d. (Box 26)
  - 2 photographs of Francis Hackett and Signe Toksvig and photo of Signe Toksvig, 1943 (Box 26)
  - 3 photographs of "The Garden at the Rectory", n.d. (Box 26)
  - Photograph of \Ellen Glasgow's birthplace with Ellen Glasgow and sister Rebe Glasgow (Box 26)
  - 9 photographs of garden of Glasgow home, n.d. (Box 26)
  - Photograph of Ellen Glasgow's study, n.d. (Box 26)
  - Photograph of front of house [Glasgow house in Richmond], 1933 (Box 26)
  - 10 photographs of various views of front of Ellen Glasgow's house in Richmond (Box 26)
  - 2 drawings of Glasgow house in Richmond by J. Lankes (Box 26)
  - Photograph of a field marked for use in Barren Ground (Box 26)
  - 2 photographs used in Barren Ground (Box 26)
  - Photograph of road used for The Battle-ground (Box 26)
  - Impression of woodcut by Lankes for The Deliverance, n.d. (Box 26)
  - 3 photographs of Richmond from Church Hill used for The Romance of a Plain Man (Box 26)
  - Photograph of courthouse mentioned in The Voice of The People, n.d. (Box 26)
  - Photograph of Capitol Square in Richmond used in The Voice of the People (Box 26)
  - 2 photographs marked for use in The Voice of the People, n.d. (Box 26)
  - 4 (2 each) of Mr. and Mrs. Chancellor Creed Taylor from portraits with explanation by Ellen Glasgow that the Taylors raised Anne Gholson Glasgow (Box 26)
  - Photographs of Roanoke River taken by Ellen Glasgow, 1898 Sep 15 (Box 26)
  - Photograph of a corn field, n.d. (Box 26)
  - Photograph of a trail through wooded area, n.d. (Box 26)
  - Photograph and negative of a sitting room with fireplace (Box 26)
  - Photograph of "Green Forest Mansion" built by Arthur Graham Glasgow, n.d. (Box 26)
  - 4 photographs of Ellen Glasgow's dogs, n.d. (Box 26)
  - Photograph of two dogs marked "Billy and Pal", 1935 (Box 26)
  - 3 photographs (Anne Gholson Glasgow, Cary Glasgow McCormack and George Walter McCormack) in black album with initials (Box 26)
  - Medal to Ellen Glasgow from Academy of Arts and Letters, 1938 Dec (Box 26)
- MEDALS AND AWARDS
  - Medal to Ellen Glasgow from National Institute of Social Sciences (Box 27)
  - Insignia of American Academy of Arts and Letters (Box 27)
  - William Dean Howell's Medal - Awarded by the American Academy of Arts and Letters, 1940 (Box 27)
  - Pulitzer Prize awarded to Ellen Glasgow- Oversize item, 1942 Jun 2 (Box 27)
- MICROFILM
  - Microfilm of Ellen Glasgow material - University of Florida (Box 27)
- PHOTOENGRAVING
  - 3 photoengravings - Newsletter XXXVI, No. 12, 1960 Aug 3; Photoengraving (Box 27)
- MANUSCRIPTS
  - A Creed, n.d.; AMsS (Box 28)
  - A Plea, n.d.; AMsS (Box 28)
- CORRESPONDENCE 1902-1937
  - Ellen Glasgow to Elizabeth Patterson, 1902 Jan 2; ALS (Box 28)
  - Ellen Glasgow to Elizabeth Patterson, 1902 Mar 22; ALS (Box 28)
  - Ellen Glasgow to Elizabeth Patterson, 1907 Aug 13; ALS (Box 28)
  - Ellen Glasgow to Elizabeth Patterson, 1907 Dec 15; ALS (Box 28)
  - Ellen Glasgow to Elizabeth Patterson, 1908 Apr-Aug; 4 APCS (Box 28)
  - Ellen Glasgow to Elizabeth Patterson, 1908 Jul 14; ALS (Box 28)
  - Ellen Glasgow to Elizabeth Patterson, 1908 Aug 13; ALS (Box 28)
  - Ellen Glasgow to Elizabeth Patterson, 1909 Aug 17; ALS (Box 28)
  - Ellen Glasgow to Elizabeth Patterson, [1909?] Sep 2; ALS (Box 28)
  - Ellen Glasgow to Elizabeth Patterson, 1909 Dec 29; ALS (Box 28)
  - Ellen Glasgow to Elizabeth Patterson, 1910 Dec 24; ALS (Box 28)
  - Ellen Glasgow to Elizabeth Patterson, 1912 Mar 29; ALS (Box 28)
  - Ellen Glasgow to Elizabeth Patterson, 1912 Oct 12; ALS (Box 28)
  - Ellen Glasgow to Julia Sully, 1913 Nov 23; ALS (Box 28)
  - Ellen Glasgow to Elizabeth Patterson, 1914 Jan 1; ALS (Box 28)
  - Ellen Glasgow to Mrs. E. M. Crutchfield, 1915 Dec 27; ALS (Box 28)
  - Ellen Glasgow to Mrs. E. M. Crutchfield, 1916 Mar 11; ALS (Box 28)
  - Ellen Glasgow to Mrs. E. M. Crutchfield, [1916?] Aug 12; APCS (Box 28)
  - Ellen Glasgow to Anne Virginia Bennett, 1927 Jul 26; ALS (Box 28)
  - Ellen Glasgow to Anne Virginia Bennett, 1927 Jul 27; ALS (Box 28)
  - Ellen Glasgow to Anne Virginia Bennett, 1927 Aug 14; ALS (Box 28)
  - Ellen Glasgow to Anne Virginia Bennett, 1927 Aug 19; ALS (Box 28)
  - Ellen Glasgow to Anne Virginia Bennett, 1927 Aug 25; ALS (Box 28)
  - Ellen Glasgow to Anne Virginia Bennett, 1927 Aug 27; ALS (Box 28)
  - Ellen Glasgow to Anne Virginia Bennett, 1927 Sep 1; ALS (Box 28)
  - Ellen Glasgow to Anne Virginia Bennett, 1927 Sep 14; ALS (Box 28)
  - Ellen Glasgow to Anne Virginia Bennett, 1929 Oct 16; ALS (Box 28)
  - Ellen Glasgow to Anne Virginia Bennett, 1930 Jun 16; ALS (Box 28)
  - Ellen Glasgow to Anne Virginia Bennett, 1930 Jun 21; ALS (Box 28)
  - Ellen Glasgow to Anne Virginia Bennett, 1930 Aug 7; ALS (Box 28)
  - Ellen Glasgow to Anne Virginia Bennett, 1930 Aug 24; ALS (Box 28)
  - Ellen Glasgow to Anne Virginia Bennett, 1931 Jun 25; ALS (Box 28)
  - Ellen Glasgow to Anne Virginia Bennett, [1935] Jun 1; ALS (Box 28)
  - Ellen Glasgow to Anne Virginia Bennett, 1935 Sep 28; ALS (Box 28)
  - Ellen Glasgow to Anne Virginia Bennett, 1935 Sep 30; ALS (Box 28)
  - Ellen Glasgow to Anne Virginia Bennett, 1937 May 19; ALS (Box 28)
  - Ellen Glasgow to Anne Virginia Bennett, 1937 Jun 1; ALS (Box 28)
  - Ellen Glasgow to Anne Virginia Bennettand others, 1922-1953; 37 APCS (Box 28)
  - Ellen Glasgow to Elizabeth Patterson, n.d.; ALS (Box 28)
  - Ellen Glasgow- Critical Essays by Stuart P. Sherman, Sara Hardt, and Emily Clark, 1929; Book (Box 28)
- MISCELLANEOUS
  - A Reunification [possibly by Cary Glasgow Tutweiler], 12 p., n.d.; AM (Box 28)
  - The Story of an Hour [possibly by Cary Glasgow Tutweiler], 12 p., n.d.; AM (Box 28)
  - Miscellaneous items, including notes, Christmas cards, and letters, including two letters from Marjorie Kinnan Rawlings, ca. 1920-1940 (Box 28)
  - 47 items, chiefly correspondence, i.e. Christmas cards and post cards, to Ellen Glasgowfrom Wallace Vernon Edenfield, Jr., ca. 1898-1942 (Box 28)
- OVERSIZE ITEMS
  - Scrapbook re: Ellen Glasgow, compiled by her sister, Rebe Glasgow Tutwiler, ca. 1920-1940
  - Woodcut, "One West Main Street, Richmond, Va. " [ Ellen Glasgow's house], by J. Lankes
  - Certificate, Pulitzer Prize in Letters, for In This Our Life, 1942 Jun 2